<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About Istio on Istio</title><link>/v1.3/about/</link><description>Recent content in About Istio on Istio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/v1.3/about/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Feature Status</title><link>/v1.3/about/feature-stages/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/about/feature-stages/</guid><description>This page lists the relative maturity and support level of every Istio feature. Please note that the phases (Alpha, Beta, and Stable) are applied to individual features within the project, not to the project as a whole. Here is a high level description of what these labels mean.
Feature phase definitions Alpha Beta Stable Purpose Demo-able, works end-to-end but has limitations. If you use it in production and encounter a serious issue we may not be able to fix it for you, so be sure that you can continue to function if you have to disable it Usable in production, not a toy anymore Dependable, production hardened API No guarantees on backward compatibility APIs are versioned Dependable, production-worthy.</description></item><item><title>Build &amp; Release Cadence</title><link>/v1.3/about/release-cadence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/about/release-cadence/</guid><description>We produce new builds of Istio for each commit. Around once a quarter or so, we build a Long Term Support (LTS) release, and run through a bunch more tests and release qualification. Finally, if we find something wrong with an LTS release, we issue patches.
The different types represent different product quality levels and different levels of support from the Istio team. In this context, support means that we will produce patch releases for critical issues and offer technical assistance.</description></item><item><title>Reporting Bugs</title><link>/v1.3/about/bugs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/about/bugs/</guid><description>Oh no! You found a bug? We&amp;rsquo;d love to hear about it.
Product bugs Search our issue database to see if we already know about your problem and learn about when we think we can fix it. If you don&amp;rsquo;t find your problem in the database, please open a new issue and let us know what&amp;rsquo;s going on.
If you think a bug is in fact a security vulnerability, please visit Reporting Security Vulnerabilities to learn what to do.</description></item><item><title>Security Vulnerabilities</title><link>/v1.3/about/security-vulnerabilities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/about/security-vulnerabilities/</guid><description>We are very grateful to the security researchers and users that report back Istio security vulnerabilities. We investigate every report thoroughly.
Reporting a vulnerability To make a report, send an email to the private istio-security-vulnerability-reports@googlegroups.com mailing list with the vulnerability details. For normal product bugs unrelated to latent security vulnerabilities, please head to our Reporting Bugs page to learn what to do.
When to report a security vulnerability? Send us a report whenever you:</description></item><item><title>Media Resources</title><link>/v1.3/about/media-resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/about/media-resources/</guid><description>Here are a few assets in case you want to show off your support for Istio, integration to Istio, or want to link back to us. Please feel free to borrow these:
White logo in minimal container, with and without Istio Blue background White logo in square container, with and without Istio Blue background Istio Blue logo in minimal container, with and without white background Istio Blue logo in square container, with and without white background Here&#39;s some advice about using these images: Cool</description></item></channel></rss>