<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mesh Expansion on Istio</title><link>/v1.3/docs/examples/mesh-expansion/</link><description>Recent content in Mesh Expansion on Istio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/v1.3/docs/examples/mesh-expansion/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Single-network Mesh Expansion</title><link>/v1.3/docs/examples/mesh-expansion/single-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/examples/mesh-expansion/single-network/</guid><description>This example provides instructions to integrate VMs and bare metal hosts into an Istio mesh deployed on Kubernetes.
Prerequisites You have already set up Istio on Kubernetes. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t done so, you can find out how in the Installation guide.
Mesh expansion machines must have IP connectivity to the endpoints in the mesh. This typically requires a VPC or a VPN, as well as a container network that provides direct (without NAT or firewall deny) routing to the endpoints.</description></item><item><title>Multi-network Mesh Expansion</title><link>/v1.3/docs/examples/mesh-expansion/multi-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/examples/mesh-expansion/multi-network/</guid><description>This example provides instructions to integrate VMs and bare metal hosts into an Istio mesh deployed on Kubernetes with gateways. No VPN connectivity nor direct network access between workloads in VMs, bare metals and clusters is required.
Prerequisites One or more Kubernetes clusters with versions: 1.13, 1.14, 1.15.
Mesh expansion machines must have IP connectivity to the Ingress gateways in the mesh.
Install the Helm client. Helm is needed to enable mesh expansion.</description></item><item><title>Bookinfo with Mesh Expansion</title><link>/v1.3/docs/examples/mesh-expansion/bookinfo-expanded/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/examples/mesh-expansion/bookinfo-expanded/</guid><description>This example deploys the Bookinfo services across Kubernetes and a set of Virtual Machines, and illustrates how to use Istio service mesh to control this infrastructure as a single mesh.
This example is still under development and only tested on Google Cloud Platform. On IBM Cloud or other platforms where overlay network of Pods is isolated from VM network, VMs cannot initiate any direct communication to Kubernetes Pods even when using Istio.</description></item></channel></rss>