<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Multi-cluster Installation on Istio</title><link>/v1.3/docs/setup/install/multicluster/</link><description>Recent content in Multi-cluster Installation on Istio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/v1.3/docs/setup/install/multicluster/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Replicated control planes</title><link>/v1.3/docs/setup/install/multicluster/gateways/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/setup/install/multicluster/gateways/</guid><description>Follow this guide to install an Istio multi-cluster deployment with replicated control plane instances in every cluster and using gateways to connect services across clusters.
Instead of using a shared Istio control plane to manage the mesh, in this configuration each cluster has its own Istio control plane installation, each managing its own endpoints. All of the clusters are under a shared administrative control for the purposes of policy enforcement and security.</description></item><item><title>Shared control plane (single-network)</title><link>/v1.3/docs/setup/install/multicluster/shared-vpn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/setup/install/multicluster/shared-vpn/</guid><description>Follow this guide to install an Istio multi-cluster service mesh where the Kubernetes cluster services and the applications in each cluster have the capability to expose their internal Kubernetes network to other clusters.
In this configuration, multiple Kubernetes clusters running a remote configuration connect to a shared Istio control plane. Once one or more remote Kubernetes clusters are connected to the Istio control plane, Envoy can then form a mesh network across multiple clusters.</description></item><item><title>Shared control plane (multi-network)</title><link>/v1.3/docs/setup/install/multicluster/shared-gateways/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/setup/install/multicluster/shared-gateways/</guid><description>Follow this guide to configure a multi-cluster mesh using a shared control plane with gateways to connect network-isolated clusters. Istio&amp;rsquo;s location-aware service routing feature is used to route requests to different endpoints, depending on the location of the request source.
By following the instructions in this guide, you will setup a two-cluster mesh as shown in the following diagram:
Shared Istio control plane topology spanning multiple Kubernetes clusters using gateways The primary cluster, cluster1, runs the full set of Istio control plane components while cluster2 only runs Istio Citadel, Sidecar Injector, and Ingress gateway.</description></item></channel></rss>