<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Telemetry on Istio</title><link>/v1.3/docs/ops/telemetry/</link><description>Recent content in Telemetry on Istio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/v1.3/docs/ops/telemetry/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Generate Istio Metrics Without Mixer [Experimental]</title><link>/v1.3/docs/ops/telemetry/in-proxy-service-telemetry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/ops/telemetry/in-proxy-service-telemetry/</guid><description>The following information describes an experimental feature, which is intended for evaluation purposes only. Istio 1.3 adds experimental support to generate service-level HTTP metrics directly in the Envoy proxies. This feature lets you continue to monitor your service meshes using the tools Istio provides without needing Mixer.
The in-proxy generation of service-level metrics replaces the following HTTP metrics that Mixer currently generates:
istio_requests_total istio_request_duration_seconds istio_request_size Enable service-level metrics generation in Envoy To generate service-level metrics directly in the Envoy proxies, follow these steps:</description></item><item><title>Envoy Statistics</title><link>/v1.3/docs/ops/telemetry/envoy-stats/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/ops/telemetry/envoy-stats/</guid><description>The Envoy proxy keeps detailed statistics about network traffic.
Envoy&amp;rsquo;s statistics only cover the traffic for a particular Envoy instance. See Telemetry for persistent per-service Istio telemetry. The statistics the Envoy proxies record can provide more information about specific pod instances.
To see the statistics for a pod:
$ kubectl exec $POD -c istio-proxy -- pilot-agent request GET stats See the Envoy documentation for an explanation of the data recorded.</description></item></channel></rss>