<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Configuration on Istio</title><link>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/</link><description>Recent content in Configuration on Istio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/v1.3/docs/reference/config/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Authentication Policy</title><link>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/istio.authentication.v1alpha1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/istio.authentication.v1alpha1/</guid><description>This package defines user-facing authentication policy.
Jwt JSON Web Token (JWT) token format for authentication as defined by RFC 7519. See OAuth 2.0 and OIDC 1.0 for how this is used in the whole authentication flow.
For example:
A JWT for any requests:
issuer: https://example.com audiences: - bookstore_android.apps.googleusercontent.com bookstore_web.apps.googleusercontent.com jwksUri: https://example.com/.well-known/jwks.json A JWT for all requests except request at path /health_check and path with prefix /status/. This is useful to expose some paths for public access but keep others JWT validated.</description></item><item><title>Resource Annotations</title><link>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/annotations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/annotations/</guid><description>This page presents the various resource annotations that Istio supports to control its behavior. Annotation Name Description kubernetes.io/ingress.class Annotation on an Ingress resources denoting the class of controllers responsible for it. networking.istio.io/exportTo Specifies the namespaces to which this service should be exported to. A value of &#39;*&#39; indicates it is reachable within the mesh &#39;.&#39; indicates it is reachable within its namespace.</description></item><item><title>Installation Options</title><link>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/installation-options/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/installation-options/</guid><description>Refer to Installation Options Changes for a detailed summary of the option changes between release 1.2 and release 1.3. To customize Istio install using Helm, use the --set &amp;lt;key&amp;gt;=&amp;lt;value&amp;gt; option in Helm command to override one or more values. The set of supported keys is shown in the table below.
certmanager options Key Default Value Description certmanager.enabled false certmanager.</description></item><item><title>Installation Options Changes</title><link>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/installation-options-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/installation-options-changes/</guid><description>The tables below show changes made to the installation options used to customize Istio install using Helm between release 1.2 and release 1.3. The tables are grouped in to three different categories:
The installation options already in the previous release but whose values have been modified in the new release. The new installation options added in the new release. The installation options removed from the new release. Modified configuration options Modified kiali key/value pairs Key Old Default Value New Default Value Old Description New Description kiali.</description></item><item><title>Operator Installation</title><link>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/istio.operator.v1alpha12.pb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/istio.operator.v1alpha12.pb/</guid><description>IstioControlPlane is a schema for both defining and customizing Istio control plane installations. Running the operator with an empty user defined InstallSpec results in an control plane with default values, using the default charts.
The simplest install specialization is to point the user InstallSpec profile to a different values file, for example an Istio minimal control plane, which will use the values associated with the minimal control plane profile for Istio.</description></item><item><title>Service Mesh</title><link>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/istio.mesh.v1alpha1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/istio.mesh.v1alpha1/</guid><description>Configuration affecting the service mesh as a whole.
AuthenticationPolicy AuthenticationPolicy defines authentication policy. It can be set for different scopes (mesh, service …), and the most narrow scope with non-INHERIT value will be used. Mesh policy cannot be INHERIT.
Name Description NONE Do not encrypt Envoy to Envoy traffic.
MUTUAL_TLS Envoy to Envoy traffic is wrapped into mutual TLS connections.</description></item></channel></rss>