<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Platform Setup on Istio</title><link>/v1.3/docs/setup/platform-setup/</link><description>Recent content in Platform Setup on Istio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/v1.3/docs/setup/platform-setup/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Alibaba Cloud</title><link>/v1.3/docs/setup/platform-setup/alicloud/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/setup/platform-setup/alicloud/</guid><description>Follow these instructions to prepare an Alibaba Cloud Kubernetes Container Service cluster for Istio. You can deploy a Kubernetes cluster to Alibaba Cloud quickly and easily in the Container Service console, which fully supports Istio.
To install and configure an Istio mesh in the Alibaba Cloud Kubernetes Container Service using the Application Catalog module, follow the Alibaba Application Catalog instructions instead. Prerequisites Follow the Alibaba Cloud instructions to activate the following services: Container Service, Resource Orchestration Service (ROS), and RAM.</description></item><item><title>Azure</title><link>/v1.3/docs/setup/platform-setup/azure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/setup/platform-setup/azure/</guid><description>Follow these instructions to prepare an Azure cluster for Istio.
You can deploy a Kubernetes cluster to Azure via AKS or AKS-Engine which fully supports Istio.
AKS You can create an AKS cluster via the az cli or the Azure portal.
For the az cli option, complete az login authentication OR use cloud shell, then run the following commands below.
Determine the desired region name which supports AKS</description></item><item><title>Docker Desktop</title><link>/v1.3/docs/setup/platform-setup/docker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/setup/platform-setup/docker/</guid><description>To run Istio with Docker Desktop, install a version which contains a supported Kubernetes version (1.13, 1.14, 1.15).
If you want to run Istio under Docker Desktop&amp;rsquo;s built-in Kubernetes, you need to increase Docker&amp;rsquo;s memory limit under the Advanced pane of Docker Desktop&amp;rsquo;s preferences. Set the resources to 8.0 GB of memory and 4 CPUs.
Docker Preferences Minimum memory requirements vary. 8 GB is sufficient to run Istio and Bookinfo.</description></item><item><title>Google Kubernetes Engine</title><link>/v1.3/docs/setup/platform-setup/gke/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/setup/platform-setup/gke/</guid><description>Google offers an add-on for GKE, which you can use instead of installing Istio manually. To determine if the add-on is right for you, refer to Istio on GKE for more information. Follow these instructions to prepare a GKE cluster for Istio.
To enable SDS in Istio, use Kubernetes 1.13 or above. Create a new cluster.
$ gcloud container clusters create &amp;lt;cluster-name&amp;gt; \ --cluster-version latest \ --num-nodes 4 \ --zone &amp;lt;zone&amp;gt; \ --project &amp;lt;project-id&amp;gt; To use the Istio CNI feature, the network-policy GKE feature must be enabled in the cluster.</description></item><item><title>IBM Cloud</title><link>/v1.3/docs/setup/platform-setup/ibm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/setup/platform-setup/ibm/</guid><description>Follow these instructions to prepare a cluster for Istio using the IBM Cloud Kubernetes Service. To install Istio on IBM Cloud Private, refer to Istio on IBM Cloud Private instead.
IBM offers a managed control plane add-on for the IBM Cloud Kubernetes Service, which you can use instead of installing Istio manually. Refer to Istio on IBM Cloud Kubernetes Service for details and instructions. To prepare a cluster before manually installing Istio, proceed as follows:</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes Gardener</title><link>/v1.3/docs/setup/platform-setup/gardener/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/setup/platform-setup/gardener/</guid><description>Bootstrapping Gardener To set up your own Gardener, see the documentation or have a look at the landscape-setup-template project. To learn more about this open source project, read the blog on kubernetes.io.
Install and configure kubectl If you already have kubectl CLI, run kubectl version --short to check the version. You need v1.10 or newer. If your kubectl is older, follow the next step to install a newer version.</description></item><item><title>MicroK8s</title><link>/v1.3/docs/setup/platform-setup/microk8s/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/setup/platform-setup/microk8s/</guid><description>Follow these instructions to prepare MicroK8s for using Istio.
Administrative privileges are required to run MicroK8s. Install the latest version of MicroK8s using the command
$ sudo snap install microk8s --classic Enable Istio with the following command:
$ microk8s.enable istio When prompted, choose whether to enforce mutual TLS authentication among sidecars. If you have a mixed deployment with non-Istio and Istio enabled services or you&amp;rsquo;re unsure, choose No.</description></item><item><title>Minikube</title><link>/v1.3/docs/setup/platform-setup/minikube/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/setup/platform-setup/minikube/</guid><description>Follow these instructions to prepare minikube for Istio installation with sufficient resources to run Istio and some basic applications.
Prerequisites Administrative privileges are required to run minikube.
To enable SDS for your mesh, you must add extra configurations to your Kubernetes deployment. Refer to the api-server reference docs for the most up-to-date flags.
Installation steps Install the latest version of minikube, version 1.1.1 or later, and a minikube hypervisor driver.</description></item><item><title>OpenShift</title><link>/v1.3/docs/setup/platform-setup/openshift/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/setup/platform-setup/openshift/</guid><description>OpenShift 4.1 and above use nftables, which is incompatible with the Istio proxy-init container. Please use CNI instead. Follow these instructions to prepare an OpenShift cluster for Istio.
By default, OpenShift doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow containers running with user ID 0. You must enable containers running with UID 0 for Istio&amp;rsquo;s service accounts:
$ oc adm policy add-scc-to-user anyuid -z istio-ingress-service-account -n istio-system $ oc adm policy add-scc-to-user anyuid -z default -n istio-system $ oc adm policy add-scc-to-user anyuid -z prometheus -n istio-system $ oc adm policy add-scc-to-user anyuid -z istio-egressgateway-service-account -n istio-system $ oc adm policy add-scc-to-user anyuid -z istio-citadel-service-account -n istio-system $ oc adm policy add-scc-to-user anyuid -z istio-ingressgateway-service-account -n istio-system $ oc adm policy add-scc-to-user anyuid -z istio-cleanup-old-ca-service-account -n istio-system $ oc adm policy add-scc-to-user anyuid -z istio-mixer-post-install-account -n istio-system $ oc adm policy add-scc-to-user anyuid -z istio-mixer-service-account -n istio-system $ oc adm policy add-scc-to-user anyuid -z istio-pilot-service-account -n istio-system $ oc adm policy add-scc-to-user anyuid -z istio-sidecar-injector-service-account -n istio-system $ oc adm policy add-scc-to-user anyuid -z istio-galley-service-account -n istio-system $ oc adm policy add-scc-to-user anyuid -z istio-security-post-install-account -n istio-system The list above accounts for the default Istio service accounts.</description></item><item><title>Oracle Cloud Infrastructure</title><link>/v1.3/docs/setup/platform-setup/oci/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/setup/platform-setup/oci/</guid><description>Follow these instructions to prepare an OKE cluster for Istio.
Create a new OKE cluster within your OCI tenancy. The simplest way to do this is by using the &amp;lsquo;Quick Cluster&amp;rsquo; option within the web console. You may also use the OCI cli as shown below.
$ oci ce cluster create --name oke-cluster1 \ --kubernetes-version &amp;lt;preferred version&amp;gt; \ --vcn-id &amp;lt;vcn-ocid&amp;gt; \ --service-lb-subnet-ids [] \ .. Retrieve your credentials for kubectl using the OCI cli.</description></item></channel></rss>