<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Adapters on Istio</title><link>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/</link><description>Recent content in Adapters on Istio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apache SkyWalking</title><link>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/apache-skywalking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/apache-skywalking/</guid><description>The SkyWalking adapter uses the Istio bypass adapter to collect metrics and make them available to Apache SkyWalking. SkyWalking provides a topology map and metrics graph to visualize the whole mesh.
This adapter supports the metric template.
Follow the official Apache SkyWalking documentation and SkyWalking k8s documentation for details on configuring SkyWalking and the Istio bypass adapter.</description></item><item><title>Apigee</title><link>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/apigee/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/apigee/</guid><description>The Apigee Mixer adapter provides Apigee&amp;rsquo;s distributed authentication and quota policy checks as well as the ingestion of Istio telemetry for analysis and reporting.
Important: The adapter is provided in an enhanced Mixer image. The default Mixer image must be replaced and the proper CRDs must be applied in order to use these features. Complete Apigee documentation on the concepts and usage of this adapter is available on the Apigee Adapter for Istio site.</description></item><item><title>App Identity and Access</title><link>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/app-identity-access-adapter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/app-identity-access-adapter/</guid><description>With the App Identity and Access Istio adapter, you can use any OIDC compliant identity provider, such as IBM Cloud App ID, to protect your APIs and containerized web apps. Without any change to your code or the need to redeploy your app, you can enforce authentication and authorization policies in all of your environments. To get started with sample configurations see the docs.</description></item><item><title>Circonus</title><link>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/circonus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/circonus/</guid><description>The circonus adapter enables Istio to deliver metric data to the Circonus monitoring backend.
This adapter supports the metric template.
Params Configuration format for the Circonus adapter.
Field Type Description submissionUrl string Circonus SubmissionURL to HTTPTrap check
submissionInterval google.protobuf.Duration metrics Params.MetricInfo[] Params.MetricInfo Describes how to represent a metric
Field Type Description name string name</description></item><item><title>CloudMonitor</title><link>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/cloudmonitor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/cloudmonitor/</guid><description>The CloudMonitor adapter enables Istio to deliver metrics to AliCloud CloudMonitor.
To push metrics to CloudMonitor using this adapter you must provide AliCloud credentials the AliCloud SDK. (see AliCloud official SDK).
The handler configuration must contain the same metrics as the instance configuration. The metrics specified in both instance and handler configurations will be sent to CloudMonitor.
This adapter supports the metric template.
Params Configuration for the cloudmonitor adapter.</description></item><item><title>CloudWatch</title><link>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/cloudwatch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/cloudwatch/</guid><description>The CloudWatch adapter enables Istio to deliver metrics to Amazon CloudWatch. Amazon CloudWatch and logs to Amazon CloudWatchLogs.
To push metrics and logs to CloudWatch using this adapter you must provide AWS credentials to the AWS SDK. (see AWS docs).
The handler configuration must contain the same metrics as the instance configuration. The metrics specified in both instance and handler configurations will be sent to CloudWatch.
This adapter supports the metric template.</description></item><item><title>Datadog</title><link>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/datadog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/datadog/</guid><description>The dogstatsd adapter is designed to deliver Istio metric instances to a listening DataDog agent.
This adapter supports the metric template.
Params Configuration parameter for the DataDog adapter. These params control how Mixer telemetry is transformed and sent to a dogstatsd agent.
The adapter assumes that a dogstatsd agent is running as a sidecar or at some other endpoint that the Mixer can reach. Any dimension that is a part of the metric is converted to a tag automatically.</description></item><item><title>Denier</title><link>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/denier/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/denier/</guid><description>The denier adapter is designed to always return a denial to precondition checks. You can specify the exact error to return for these denials.
This adapter supports the checknothing template, the listentry template, and the quota template.
Params Configuration format for the Denier adapter.
Field Type Description status google.rpc.Status The error to return when denying a request.
validDuration google.protobuf.Duration The duration for which the denial is valid.</description></item><item><title>Fluentd</title><link>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/fluentd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/fluentd/</guid><description>The fluentd adapter is designed to deliver Istio log entries to a listening fluentd daemon.
This adapter supports the logentry template.
Params Configuration parameters for the fluentd adapter.
This adapter accepts logentry instance. It then routes those logentries to a listening fluentd daemon with minimal transformation. Fluentd uses a &amp;ldquo;tag&amp;rdquo; for all logs. The &amp;ldquo;Name&amp;rdquo; of the logentry is used as the &amp;ldquo;tag&amp;rdquo;, unless the logentry already has a variable &amp;ldquo;tag&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes Env</title><link>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/kubernetesenv/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/kubernetesenv/</guid><description>The kubernetesenv adapter extracts information from a Kubernetes environment and produces attributes that can be used in downstream adapters.
This adapter supports the kubernetes template.
Params Configuration parameters for the kubernetes adapter. These params control the manner in which the kubernetes adapter discovers and generates values related to pod information.
The adapter works by looking up pod information by UIDs (of the form: &amp;ldquo;kubernetes://pod.namespace&amp;rdquo;). It expects that the UIDs will be supplied in an input map for three distinct traffic classes (source, destination, and origin).</description></item><item><title>List</title><link>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/list/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/list/</guid><description>The list adapter makes it possible to perform simple whitelist or blacklist checks. You can configure the adapter with the list to check, or you can point it to a URL from where the list should be fetched. Lists can be simple strings, IP addresses, or regex patterns.
This adapter supports the listentry template.
Params Configuration format for the list adapter.
Field Type Description providerUrl string Where to find the list to check against.</description></item><item><title>Memory quota</title><link>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/memquota/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/memquota/</guid><description>The memquota adapter can be used to support Istio&amp;rsquo;s quota management system. Although functional, this adapter is not intended for production use and is suited for local testing only. The reason for this limitation is that this adapter can only be used in meshes where there is a single instance of Mixer running for the whole mesh (i.e. non-HA configuration) and if that single instance crashes, all outstanding quota values will be lost.</description></item><item><title>OPA</title><link>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/opa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/opa/</guid><description>The opa adapter exposes an Open Policy Agent engine that provides sophisticated access control mechanisms.
This adapter supports the authorization template.
Params Configuration format for the opa adapter.
Example configuration:
policy: - |+ package mixerauthz policy = [ &amp;lbrace; &amp;quot;rule&amp;quot;: &amp;lbrace; &amp;quot;verbs&amp;quot;: [ &amp;quot;storage.buckets.get&amp;quot; ], &amp;quot;users&amp;quot;: [ &amp;quot;bucket-admins&amp;quot; ] } } ] default allow = false allow = true &amp;lbrace; rule = policy[_].rule input.subject.user = rule.users[_] input.action.method = rule.verbs[_] } checkMethod: &amp;quot;data.</description></item><item><title>Prometheus</title><link>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/prometheus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/prometheus/</guid><description>The prometheus adapter collects Istio metrics and makes them available to Prometheus.
This adapter supports the metric template.
Params Configuration format for the prometheus adapter.
Field Type Description metrics Params.MetricInfo[] The set of metrics to represent in Prometheus. If a metric is defined in Istio but doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a corresponding shape here, it will not be populated at runtime.
metricsExpirationPolicy Params.MetricsExpirationPolicy Optional.</description></item><item><title>Redis Quota</title><link>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/redisquota/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/redisquota/</guid><description>The redisquota adapter can be used to support Istio&amp;rsquo;s quota management system. It depends on a Redis server to store quota values.
This adapter supports the quota template.
Params redisquota adapter supports the rate limit quota using either fixed or rolling window algorithm. And it is using Redis as a shared data storage.
Example configuration:
redisServerUrl: localhost:6379 connectionPoolSize: 10 quotas: - name: requestcount.quota.istio-system maxAmount: 50 validDuration: 60s bucketDuration: 1s rateLimitAlgorithm: ROLLING_WINDOW overrides: - dimensions: destination: ratings source: reviews maxAmount: 12 - dimensions: destination: reviews maxAmount: 5 Field Type Description quotas Params.</description></item><item><title>SignalFx</title><link>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/signalfx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/signalfx/</guid><description>The signalfx adapter collects Istio metrics and trace spans and sends them to SignalFx.
This adapter supports the metric template and the tracespan template.
If sending trace spans, this adapter can make use of certain conventions in the tracespan format that is configured to send to this adapter. Here is an example tracespan spec that will work well:
apiVersion: config.istio.io/v1alpha2 kind: instance metadata: name: signalfx spec: compiledTemplate: tracespan params: traceId: request.</description></item><item><title>SolarWinds</title><link>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/solarwinds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/solarwinds/</guid><description>The solarwinds adapter enables Istio to deliver log and metric data to the Papertrail logging backend and the AppOptics monitoring backend.
This adapter supports the metric template and the logentry template.
Params Configuration format for the solarwinds adapter.
Example config usage:
apiVersion: &amp;quot;config.istio.io/v1alpha2&amp;quot; kind: handler metadata: name: solarwinds namespace: istio-system spec: compiledAdapter: solarwinds params: appoptics_access_token: &amp;lt;APPOPTICS SAMPLE TOKEN&amp;gt; papertrail_url: &amp;lt;PAPERTRAIL URL&amp;gt; papertrail_local_retention_duration: &amp;lt;RETENTION PERIOD FOR LOGS LOCALLY, Optional&amp;gt; metrics: requestcount.</description></item><item><title>Stackdriver</title><link>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/stackdriver/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/stackdriver/</guid><description>The stackdriver adapter enables Istio to deliver log, metric and traces to the Stackdriver backend.
This adapter supports the metric template, the logentry template, and the tracespan template.
Params Configuration format for the stackdriver adapter.
Field Type Description endpoint string Endpoint URL to send stackdriver data - leave empty to use the StackDriver SDK&amp;rsquo;s default value (monitoring.googleapis.com).
projectId string GCP Project to attach metrics to.</description></item><item><title>StatsD</title><link>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/statsd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/statsd/</guid><description>The statsd adapter enables Istio to deliver metric data to a StatsD monitoring backend.
This adapter supports the metric template.
Params Configuration format for the statsd adapter.
Field Type Description address string Address of the statsd server, e.g. localhost:8125
prefix string Metric prefix, do not specify for no prefix
flushDuration google.protobuf.Duration FlushDuration controls the maximum amount of time between sending metrics to the statsd collection server.</description></item><item><title>Stdio</title><link>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/stdio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/stdio/</guid><description>The stdio adapter enables Istio to output logs and metrics to the local machine. Logs and metrics can be directed to Mixer&amp;rsquo;s standard output stream, standard error stream, or to any locally reachable file. When outputting to files, you can enable file rotation such that the adapter will automatically manage a set of file backups as data is generated.
This adapter supports the logentry template. and the metric template.
Params Configuration format for the stdio adapter</description></item><item><title>Wavefront by VMware</title><link>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/wavefront/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/wavefront/</guid><description>The wavefront adapter collects metrics and makes them available to Wavefront by VMware.
This adapter supports the metric template.
Params Configuration format for the wavefront adapter.
Field Type Description direct Params.WavefrontDirect (oneof) The credentials for direct ingestion.
proxy Params.WavefrontProxy (oneof) The credentials for ingestion via a Wavefront Proxy.
flushInterval google.protobuf.Duration The metrics flush interval.
source string The source tag for all metrics handled by this adapter.</description></item><item><title>Zipkin</title><link>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/zipkin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/reference/config/policy-and-telemetry/adapters/zipkin/</guid><description>The zipkin adapter enables Istio to deliver tracing data to the Zipkin tracing backend.
This adapter supports the tracespan template.
Params Configuration format for the zipkin adapter.
Field Type Description url string URL of Zipkin HTTP endpoint.
Required.
sampleProbability double Uniform probability that a trace will be sampled. Defaults to 0 (sampling disabled) if unset.
Optional.</description></item></channel></rss>