<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Contributing to the Docs on Istio</title><link>/v1.3/about/contribute/</link><description>Recent content in Contributing to the Docs on Istio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/v1.3/about/contribute/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Creating and Editing Pages</title><link>/v1.3/about/contribute/creating-and-editing-pages/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/about/contribute/creating-and-editing-pages/</guid><description>This page shows how to create, test, and maintain Istio documentation topics.
Before you begin Before you can work on Istio documentation, you first need to create a fork of the Istio documentation repository as described in Working with GitHub.
Choosing a page type As you prepare to write a new topic, think about which of these page types is the best fit for your content:
Concept A concept page explains some significant aspect of Istio.</description></item><item><title>Style Guide</title><link>/v1.3/about/contribute/style-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/about/contribute/style-guide/</guid><description>This page provides the content guidelines for the Istio documentation. These guidelines do not supersede your best judgment and enhancements to this document in a pull request are welcome.
Formatting standards Use consistent capitalization Don&amp;rsquo;t use capitalization for emphasis.
Follow the original capitalization employed in the code or configuration files when referencing those values directly. Use back-ticks `` around the referenced content to make the connection explicit. For example, use IstioRoleBinding, not Istio Role Binding or istio role binding.</description></item><item><title>Working with GitHub</title><link>/v1.3/about/contribute/github/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/about/contribute/github/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re excited that you&amp;rsquo;re interested in contributing to improve and expand our docs! Please take a few moments to get familiar with our procedures before you get started.
To work on Istio documentation, you need to:
Create a GitHub account.
Sign the Contributor License Agreement.
The documentation is published under the Apache 2.0 license.
How to contribute There are three ways you can contribute to the Istio documentation:</description></item><item><title>Diagram Creation Guidelines</title><link>/v1.3/about/contribute/diagrams/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/about/contribute/diagrams/</guid><description>Welcome to the Istio diagram guide!
The guide is available as an SVG file or as a Google Draw file to allow you to reuse the shapes and styles with ease. Use these guidelines to create SVG diagrams for the Istio website using any vector graphics tool like Google Draw, InkScape, or Illustrator. Please ensure that the text in your diagrams remains editable.
Our goal is to drive consistency across all diagrams in our website to ensure diagrams are clear, technically accurate, and accessible.</description></item></channel></rss>