<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Traffic Management on Istio</title><link>/v1.3/docs/ops/traffic-management/</link><description>Recent content in Traffic Management on Istio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/v1.3/docs/ops/traffic-management/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction to Network Operations</title><link>/v1.3/docs/ops/traffic-management/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/ops/traffic-management/introduction/</guid><description>This section is intended as a guide to operators of an Istio based deployment. It will provide information an operator of a Istio deployment would need to manage the networking aspects of an Istio service mesh. Much of the information and many of the procedures that an Istio operator would require are already documented in other sections of the Istio documentation so this section will rely heavily on pointers to that other content.</description></item><item><title>Avoiding Traffic Management Issues</title><link>/v1.3/docs/ops/traffic-management/deploy-guidelines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/ops/traffic-management/deploy-guidelines/</guid><description>This section provides specific deployment or configuration guidelines to avoid networking or traffic management issues.
Cross-namespace configuration sharing You can define virtual services, destination rules, or service entries in one namespace and then reuse them in other namespaces, if they are exported to those namespaces. Istio exports all traffic management resources to all namespaces by default, but you can override the visibility with the exportTo field. For example, only clients in the same namespace can use the following virtual service:</description></item><item><title>Locality Load Balancing</title><link>/v1.3/docs/ops/traffic-management/locality-load-balancing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/ops/traffic-management/locality-load-balancing/</guid><description>A locality defines a geographic location within your mesh using the following triplet:
Region Zone Sub-zone The geographic location typically represents a data center. Istio uses this information to prioritize load balancing pools to control the geographic location where requests are sent.
Configuring Locality Load Balancing This feature is enabled by default. To disable locality load balancing, pass the --set global.localityLbSetting.enabled=false flag when installing Istio.
Requirements Currently, the service discovery platform populates the locality automatically.</description></item><item><title>Protocol Selection</title><link>/v1.3/docs/ops/traffic-management/protocol-selection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/v1.3/docs/ops/traffic-management/protocol-selection/</guid><description>Istio supports proxying all TCP traffic by default, but in order to provide additional capabilities, such as routing and rich metrics, the protocol must be determined. This can be done automatically or explicitly specified.
Automatic Protocol Selection By default, Istio will automatically detect HTTP and HTTP/2 traffic. If the protocol cannot automatically be determined, traffic will be treated as plain TCP traffic.
This feature can be turned off by providing the Helm value --set pilot.</description></item></channel></rss>